Finding Aid for Grand Hotel (Mackinac Island, Mich.) Records, ca. 1855-2012
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Grand Hotel (Mackinac Island, Mich.) records
circa 1855-2012
1946-2012
Grand Hotel (Mackinac Island, Mich.)
05146 Bb 2 Bb outsize; UBB1
The Grand Hotel records comprise documents, photographs, audio and videographic material collected about the hotel by its management. The strength of the collection is in its documentation of the guest experience at the hotel, and the evolution of amenities offered by the hotel during the mid-to-late 20th century. A small number of items also provide a glimpse of the hotel’s earliest days as a summer resort.
25.5 linear feet in 27 boxes
2 oversize folders
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group was received from Grand Hotel (donor no. 9662 ) beginning in October 2005; additional materials have been received.
Periodic additions to the records expected.
The record group is open to research. Copying for commercial purposes requires the permission of the donor.
Grand Hotel opened on July 10, 1887 as a venture of the Mackinac Island Hotel Company. In 1910, the hotel was purchased by Henry Weaver, its manager since 1900. The hotel was sold again in 1918, this time to J. Logan Ballard, who died only five years later. In 1925, William Stewart Woodfill purchased the hotel with two other men, to whom he later sold his shares. In 1933, Woodfill would purchase the hotel again, this time as sole owner, after it fell into receivership. Woodfill, who also managed the hotel for a number of years, retained ownership throughout the mid-20th century, though he gradually turned responsibility for the hotel's management over to Dan Musser beginning in 1951. The Musser family purchased the hotel from Woodfill in 1979, and continue to run it today.
Since its opening, Grand Hotel has become a popular family vacation destination and conference location with its upscale accommodations and dining facilities. Features of the hotel include an elaborate, multi-course dinner included for every guest, 18 holes of golf, a 660-foot front porch overlooking the water, and a pool that Esther Williams made famous in the movie This Time For Keeps in 1946.
Information for this History was taken from Grand Hotel: The biography of an American institution by John McCabe. This book, published by the hotel on the occasion of its centennial season, is available in box 1 of the papers, and includes images of historical documents owned by the hotel and other repositories that are not included in this collection.
The Grand Hotel records are arranged in six series: Printed Material, 1901-2007; Miscellaneous, 1935-1992; Press Clippings and Publications, 1965-2011; Photographic Material, 1855-2004; Audio Material, 1981-2007; and Videographic Material, 1980-2011.
Subjects:
Grand Hotel (Mackinac Island, Mich.); Hotels--Michigan--Mackinac Island.; Summer resorts--Michigan--Mackinac Island.; Mackinac Island (Mich.)
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Bush, George W. (George Walker), 1946-; Clinton, Hillary Rodham.; Dewey, Thomas E. (Thomas Edmund), 1902-1971.; Engler, John, 1948-; Milliken, William G., 1922-; Reeve, Christopher, 1952-2004.; Seymour, Jane, 1951-; Truman, Harry S., 1884-1972.; Warren, Earl, 1891-1974.; Williams, G. Mennen, 1911-1988.; Grand Hotel (Mackinac Island, Mich.); Construction--Michigan--Mackinac Island.; Mackinac Island (Mich.); Motion picture locations--Michigan--Mackinac Island.; Hotels--Michigan--Mackinac Island.; Resorts--Michigan--Mackinac Island.
Genre Terms:
Menus.; Photographs.; Sound recordings.; Videotapes.
- Printed Material, circa 1920-2007
  Printed Material, ca. 1920- 2007, comprises mostly materials printed for use in the regular course of the hotel's business, such as brochures, menus, guest identification/information booklets, and similar items. Items of note include an early brochure featuring photographs of guest rooms (stored as an oversize item) and a subseries of menus used at the hotel throughout the 20th century. Also included in this series is a copy of the hardbound book Grand Hotel: The biography of an American institution by John McCabe.
  - Convention-specific Materials
    - Baggage claim tags (Box 1)
    - Programs, 1945-1987; 1962-1969; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Marketing Materials
    - Advertisement from Collier's Weekly, July 13, 1901 (Folder Bb)
    - Brochures, general (Box 1)
      (also one oversize item in folder Bb Outsize)
    - Brochures on getting to Grand Hotel (Box 1)
    - Marketing Folders, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Meeting facilities photographs and specs (Box 1)
    - Rate schedules (Box 1)
    - Season calendars and events (Box 1)
    - Winter address change notices (Box 1)
  - Menus
    - Breakfast (Box 1)
    - Box Lunches (Box 1)
    - Luncheon and Snack Bar (Box 1)
    - Dinner (Box 1)
    - Children (Box 1)
    - Wine and Beverage (Box 1)
    - Desserts (Box 1)
    - Specialty Restaurants, Bars and Banquets (Box 1)
  - Newsletters
    - "Grand Hotel News", 1926-1927; undated (Box 1)
    - "Island Items", circa 1973-1974 (Box 1)
    - "Grand News from Mackinac", 1980; Spring 1984; circa 1985; 1989 (Box 1)
    - Grand Hotel Grapevine (employee newsletter) (Box 1)
  - Other Printed Material
    - Business Cards (Box 1)
    - Floor plans of the hotel (Box 1)
    - Flyer naming R. Daniel Musser "Resort Executive of the Year", 1980 (Box 1)
    - Gift Catalogs (Box 1)
    - Golf Score Cards (Box 1)
    - Grand Hotel, The Biography of an American Institution by John McCabe (3rd edn., 1993) (Box 1)
    - Guest Identification/Information booklets and cards; songbooks (Box 1)
    - Guest Information (Box 1)
    - Holiday Cards (Box 1)
    - Hotel Forms (Box 1)
      (guest bill, application for employment, etc.)
    - Mackinac Island miscellaneous (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous brochures and maps mentioning Grand Hotel (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous printed items (Box 1)
      (labels, note paper, etc.)
    - Post cards and negative prints for post cards (Box 1)
    - Lobby posters for "This Time for Keeps" (Box 1)
      (in oversize folder UBBl)
    - Press book and related publicity for "This Time for Keeps" (Folder 1)
      (located in Bb)
    - Press Releases (Box 1)
    - Reservation and Confirmation cards (Box 1)
- Miscellaneous, 1935-1992
  Miscellaneous, 1935-1992, comprises a small number of internal memoranda, a proof sheet for a page reprinting a Ripley's Believe It or Not regarding Grand Hotel's porch and the text of a speech dedicating Grand Hotel as a National Historic Landmark in 1990.
  - Historical background information (Box 1)
  - Internal Memoranda, 1935-1992 (Box 1)
  - Marketing correspondence (Box 1)
  - Proof sheet for page reprinting a Ripley's Believe It or Not regarding Grand Hotel's porch, 1986 (Box 1)
  - Grand Hotel Centennial Weekend and other celebrations, July 10-12, 1987 (Box 1)
  - Text of speech dedicating Grand Hotel as a National Historic Landmark, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Additions received, 2006-2007
    - Marketing (Box 19)
    - Menus and others, 1992-1993; 3 folders (Box 19)
    - Other printed (Box 19)
    - "Michigan's Island Innkeeper," in Saturday Evening Post, June 4, 1960 (Box 19)
- Press Clippings and Publications, 1965-2011
  The Press Clippings and Publications series comprises newspaper and magazine articles about Grand Hotel that were saved by its public relations office.
  - Pre-1975 (Box 2)
  - 1975-1982 (Box 2)
  - 1983-1986 (Box 25)
  - 1986-1988 (Box 3)
  - 1989-1991 (Box 26)
  - 1992-1995 (Box 4)
  - 1996-1998 (Box 11)
  - 1999-2002 (Box 12)
  - 2003-2004 (Box 13)
  - 2005-2006 (Box 14)
  - 2007 (Box 18)
  - 2008-2009 (Box 20)
  - 2010 (Box 22)
  - 2011 (Box 23)
  - 2012 (Box 27)
    (with 125th anniversary flag)
- Photographic Material, circa 1855-2004
  Photographic Material, 1855-2004 comprises over 2,200 images organized in 5 subseries. Hotel Amenities, Scenery and Unidentified Events comprises images of the hotel, its surroundings, and general unidentified events. The bulk of the images in this subseries are from the mid-20th century through the late 1980s. The Events subseries comprises images of identified events that were held at the hotel, and includes numerous photographs of celebrities and political leaders. People contains images featuring notable personages and staff members, and includes several images of Woodfill and the Musser family. Construction and Remodeling contains almost entirely snapshot images of construction projects that were conducted at the hotel during its off-seasons, mainly during the 1980s. Finally, the Miscellaneous subseries contains images of the recovery work after a room fire at the hotel in 1983, as well as photographic reproductions of several artistic and historical items related to the hotel.
  - Hotel Amenities, Scenery and Unidentified Events
    - Early images of Grand Hotel and Mackinac Is, circa pre-1920; 27 prints (Box 5)
    - Hotel Amenities
      - undated, 20 color film slides and 2 b/w negatives (Box 5)
      - undated, 28 prints various prints (Box 5)
      - undated, 29 prints various b/w prints (Box 5)
      - 1984, undated; 43 prints various prints (Box 5)
    - Hotel Amenities and Unidentified Events
      - circa 1950s-1970s, 62 prints in 2 envelopes bulk b/w prints (Box 5)
      - circa 1960s-1980s, 27 prints bulk 8"x10" b/w prints (Box 5)
    - Catering Staff and Facilities, circa 1978; 40 prints 3 1/2" x 4 1/2" color snapshots (Box 5)
    - Golf Course, October 25, 1986; 65 prints 5" x 7" color prints (Box 5)
    - Rooms and Suites, undated; 19 prints 8" x 10" color prints (Box 5)
    - Scenery, 1987; 8 prints 8" x 10" color prints (Box 5)
  - Events
    - "This Time For Keeps" Movie Shoot, 1946; 77 prints in 2 envelopes 8"x10" b/w prints (Box 5)
    - Michigan Savings and Loan Event, circa 1975; 21 prints 8" x 10" b/w prints (Box 5)
    - NASA Reception set up with silver service and staff, 1977; 38 prints 3 1/2" x 3 1/2" color snapshots (Box 5)
    - Michigan Bankers' Association Hawaiian Luau, 1978; 13 prints 5"x7" color prints (Box 5)
    - Knights of Columbus Event, 1983; 22 prints 5"x7" color prints (Box 5)
    - Events, 1983; 15 prints 5"x7" color prints (Box 5)
      (includes images of Flip Wilson, Governor Blanchard and Governor DuPont)
    - Events, 1987; 13 prints Bulk 8"x10" color prints (Box 5)
    - Democratic Governors' Association Event, July 1987; 17 prints 3"x5" color snapshots (Box 5)
      (includes images of Musser with Bill and Hillary Clinton, and Jesse Jackson)
    - Democratic Governors' Association, circa 1988; 68 prints 5"x7" color prints (Box 5)
    - 100th Anniversary Party, 1987; 24 prints color snapshots (Box 5)
    - 100th Anniversary Party, 1987; 235 prints in 3 envelopes 5"x7" color prints (Box 5)
      (includes images of Esther Williams)
    - Tea with John McCabe, author of Grand Hotel, circa 1987; 23 prints 5"x7" color prints (Box 5)
    - MLSI Banquet, 1988; 18 prints 5"x7" color prints (Box 5)
    - Victorian Weekend, 1988; 32 prints 5"x7" color prints (Box 5)
    - Okemos Office Open House, December 1990; 25 prints color snapshots (Box 5)
    - Republican Party Event, circa 1990; 20 prints 5"x7" color prints (Box 5)
      (includes images of Robert Dole and other prominent Republican leaders)
    - Newsletter Photographs of Events, undated; 11 prints 5"x7" color prints (Box 5)
      (includes images of John Engler)
    - "Somewhere In Time" Period Costume Event, undated; 65 prints 5"x7" color prints (Box 5)
    - James Beard House Dinner, March 18, 2004; 260 JPEG images on CD-ROM (Box 5)
  - People
    - Notable Personages, bulk political, bulk 8"x10" prints (Box 5)
    - Notable Personages - Gerald R. Ford (Box 5)
    - Staff and Notable Personages, 61 prints various prints, bulk color (Box 5)
      (includes images of Governor Blanchard, John Paul Stevens, Phyllis Diller, the Grand Hotel Orchestra, Ramsey Miller, etc.)
    - Musser Family, W. Stewart Woodfill, and Grand Hotel Executives, 15 prints (Box 5)
  - Construction and Remodeling
    - Water Tower Removal, undated; 18 prints color snapshots (Box 6)
    - Woodville Housing Project, December 1987; 5 prints Polaroids (Box 6)
    - General Construction and Remodeling
      - Undated, possibly, circa 1960; 5 prints 8"x10" b/w prints (Box 6)
      - 1977, 7 prints 8"x10" b/w prints (Box 6)
      - May 1985, 15 prints color snapshots (Box 6)
      - November 1985, 73 prints color snapshots (Box 6)
        (includes golf course and pool remodeling)
      - December 1985, 38 prints color snapshots (Box 6)
      - November 1986, 45 prints color snapshots (Box 6)
      - December 1986, 21 prints color snapshots (Box 6)
      - January 1987, 53 prints color snapshots (Box 6)
      - March 1987, 56 prints color snapshots (Box 6)
        (includes Corner Cottage)
      - Undated, possibly, 1987; 15 prints color snapshots (Box 6)
      - Winter 1988-1989, 135 prints in 3 envelopes color snapshots (Box 6)
        (were originally organized in six mini-albums)
      - Winter 1988-1989, 94 prints in 2 envelopes color snapshots (Box 7)
        (were originally in an album titled "Scenes and Construction")
      - Undated, 41 prints color snapshots (Box 7)
      - Undated, 30 prints 18 Polaroids and 12 color snapshots (Box 7)
      - Undated, 48 prints color snapshots (Box 7)
      - Undated, 12 prints color snapshots (Box 7)
      - Undated, 37 prints color snapshots (Box 7)
      - Undated, 36 prints color snapshots (Box 7)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Images of fire recovery, Room 258, May 10, 1983; 75 prints 5"x7" color prints (Box 7)
    - Mackinac Island and Grand Hotel Art and Historical Items, 1855-1945 (scattered); 13 prints; 1 optical disks DVD; 1 optical disks CD-ROMs (Box 7)
    - Marketing images, 4 optical disks CD-ROMs (Box 7)
    - The Art of Hospitality exhibit, 2012; 1 optical disks CD-ROMs (Box 7)
  - Display Photographs, 1855-1995
    Photographs that were once displayed on the walls of the Grand Hotel can be found in the Display Photographs, 1856-1995 subseries. Beginning in 2006, a small group of photographs were transferred to the Bentley Historical Library. The Bentley scanned, color corrected, and printed copies of these photographs and returned the copies to the Grand Hotel; the originals are preserved in this collection. Some photographs are severely faded due to years of sun exposure. The display photographs have been divided into similar groupings as the Photographic Material: Hotel and Grounds, Mackinac Island, Events, People, and Construction. Additional accruals to this series are expected.
    - Project documentation
      - 2006-2007 (Box 16)
      - 2007-2008 (Box 16)
      - 2008-2009 (Box 16)
    - Hotel and Grounds
      - Grand Hotel images, circa 1888; 10 prints (Box 16)
        (8 exterior, 2 interior)
        (nos. 1a-1j)
      - Grand Hotel and grounds, 1900s; 5 prints (Box 16)
        (nos. 3a-3e)
      - "Music Room, with finest Zenith radio, now the Bellman's Office, c. 1930" (Box 17)
        (no. 7)
      - "Grand Hotel porch as first built in 1887", 3 prints (Box 16)
        (nos. 19a-19c)
      - Horse and sleigh combinations, 5 prints (Box 16)
        (nos. 20a-20e)
      - Horse and carriage combinations, 3 prints (Box 16)
        (nos.26a-26c)
      - Interior rooms, 2 prints (Box 21)
        (no. 27)
      - Interior rooms, 2 prints (Box 17)
        (no. 28)
      - "The main lobby, now the parlor, c. 1937" (Box 21)
        (no. 29)
      - "The casino, now the theater, 1940", 3 prints (Box 17)
        (nos. 30a-30b and 31)
      - Grand Hotel coach scene (Box 17)
        (no. 101)
      - Grand Hotel scenes, Dave Rogers:, 1900
        - From a distance (Box 16)
          (no. 103a)
        - With man in foreground (Box 16)
          (no. 103b)
      - Porch from above (Box 21)
        (no. 105)
      - Color interiors, 1941
        - Theatre (Box 16)
          (no. 107)
        - Parlor (Box 16)
          (no. 108)
        - Bar (Box 16)
          (no. 109)
        - Terrace Room (Box 16)
          (no. 110)
      - Grand Hotel from southeast in winter (Box 21)
        (no. 111)
      - Hotel exteriors, Cynthia Ellis: Grand Hotel from south (Box 17)
        (no. 120a)
      - Hotel exteriors, Cynthia Ellis:
        - Carriage at front entrance (Box 16)
          (no. 120b)
        - Porch from west (Box 16)
          (no. 120c)
        - Garden (Box 16)
          (no. 120d)
      - Hotel signs:
        - "Purest air" (Box 16)
          (no. 121a)
        - "Proper dress" (Box 16)
          (no. 121b)
        - "Dress requirements" (Box 16)
          (no. 121c)
        - "Driveway and sidewalk" (Box 16)
          (no. 121d)
      - Dining Room, mid 20th century (Box 17)
        (no. 128)
      - Casino with slot machines (Box 16)
        (no. 129)
      - Grand Hotel porch, circa, 1938 (Box 17)
        (no. 201 oversize box 17)
      - Grand Hotel behind shore ice, winter 1980 (Box 16)
        (no. 203)
      - Grand Hotel dray with barrels of flour (Box 21)
        (no. 204 oversize box 21)
      - Grand Hotel interiors, 1940
        - Terrace Room (Box 16)
          (no. 205a)
        - Cocktail Lounge (later Audubon Bar) (Box 16)
          (no. 205b)
        - Lobby (later Parlor) (Box 16)
          (no. 205c)
        - Marine Room (later Cottage) (Box 16)
          (no. 205d)
      - Tea dance time in the Grand Hotel's Tea Gardens, 1920s (Box 16)
        (no. 207)
      - Plank's Grand Hotel, photo of a print (Box 16)
        (no. 208)
      - Veranda looking toward the Straits, photo of a print (Box 16)
        (no. 210)
      - Porte-cochere and entrance, Plank's Grand Hotel, photo of a print (Box 16)
        (no. 211)
      - Grand Hotel, a projected fantasy sketched in, 1887; photo of a print (Box 16)
        (no. 212)
      - Projected view of expanded Grand Hotel, photo of a print (Box 16)
        (no. 214)
      - Main lobby, now the parlor, circa 1937 (Box 21)
        (no. 216, oversize box 21)
      - Grand Hotel behind large pile of shore ice (Box 21)
        (no. 218, oversize box 21)
      - Grand Hotel porch view (Box 17)
        (no. 219, oversize box 17)
      - Coast Guard icebreaker Mackinaw with Grand Hotel in background (Box 16)
        (no. 220)
      - Governor's residence (Box 21)
        (no. 223, oversize box 21)
      - Dog sleds in front of Grand Hotel (Box 21)
        (no. 224, oversize box 21)
      - Grand Hotel architect's rendering, 1887; photo of a print (Box 21)
        (no. 225, oversize box 21)
      - Culinary Department, Plank's Grand Hotel, photo of a print (Box 16)
        (no. 226)
    - Mackinac Island
      - "Exhibition in Mackinac Harbor, August 9, 1886" (Box 16)
        (no. 2)
      - "Mackinac Island in 1880" view of Main and Market Streets from the Fort (Box 17)
        (no. 5)
      - Arnold Line docks (Box 16)
        (no. 9)
      - "Mackinac in 1856" Market St. (Box 16)
        (no. 18)
      - Old fort scene (Box 16)
        (no. 104)
      - Island scenes (1), 1890s
        - Sugar Loaf (Box 16)
          (no. 117a)
        - Arch Rock (Box 16)
          (no. 117b)
        - Devil's Kitchen? (Box 16)
          (no. 117c)
        - Shore Road (Box 16)
          (no. 117d)
      - Island scenes (2), 1890s
        - Round Island (Box 16)
          (no. 117e)
        - Grand Hotel from southeast (Box 16)
          (no. 117f)
        - West Bluff cottages (Box 16)
          (no. 117g)
      - Early Mackinac, 1870 (Box 17)
        (no. 118)
      - Bark shanties, circa 1888 (Box 16)
        (no. 124)
      - Woodfill house with dogsled (Box 16)
        (no. 125)
      - Winter scenes (1), January 1943
        - Grand Hotel in distance (Box 16)
          (no. 202a)
        - View from fort (Box 16)
          (no. 202b)
        - Blockhouse (Box 16)
          (no. 202c)
        - Main St. (Box 16)
          (no. 202d)
        - Sleigh on Main St. (Box 16)
          (no. 202e)
        - Friend bicycling (Box 16)
          (no. 202f)
        - Woodfill bicycling (Box 16)
          (no. 202g)
        - Woodfill and friend posing with broken shore ice (Box 16)
          (no. 202h)
        - Climbing on shore ice (Box 16)
          (no. 202i)
        - Walking along shore ice (Box 16)
          (no. 202j)
      - Winter scenes (2), January 1943
        - Broken ice with Round Island in distance (Box 16)
          (no. 202k)
        - Woodfill home (Box 16)
          (no. 202l)
        - Woodfill home from distance (Box 16)
          (no. 202m)
        - Sleigh approaching island (Box 16)
          (no. 202n)
        - Sleigh crossing ice (Box 16)
          (no. 202o)
        - Horse and people walking across ice (Box 16)
          (no. 202p)
        - Sleigh crossing ice (Box 16)
          (no. 202q)
        - W. Stewart Woodfill and friend in sleigh (Box 16)
          (no. 202r)
        - Sleigh passing ferry City of Petoskey (Box 16)
          (no. 202s)
        - St. Ignace street scene (Box 16)
          (no. 202t)
      - Last of the bark shanties at Mackinac, circa 1888 (Box 16)
        (no. 221)
    - Events
      - "'Somewhere in Time' filmed on location at Grand Hotel 1979", 12 prints (Box 16)
        (includes photographs of Christopher Reeve and Jane Seymour)
        (nos. 23a-23l)
      - "GOP at Mackinac, September 1979", 8 images (Box 16)
        (includes photographs of Ambassador Bush, Governor Milliken, Senator Baker, Lt. Governor Brickley, Committeeman Fletcher, Senator Griffin, Chairman Larsen, and Commerce Director McLaughlin)
        (nos. 8a-8h)
      - "A porch scene during the Governors' Conference of 1945" (Box 21)
        (no. 12; oversize box 21)
      - "President Harry S. Truman, conference of Michigan Democrats", August 30, 1950; 8 prints (Box 16)
        (includes photos of G. Mennen Williams)
        (nos. 21a-21h)
      - Platform Committee, Democratic National Convention, 1988 (Box 16)
        (no. 15c)
      - "The big Budweiser Clydesdales stopped at Grand Hotel, but in the stables, of course" (Box 17)
        (no. 14)
      - "The Republican Foreign Policy Conference..." (Box 17)
        (no. 25)
      - Michigan Hotel Association banquet in casino, 1941 (Box 16)
        (no. 119)
      - World Conference on Large Lakes and Greater Detroit Chamber of Commerce, early spring 1986
        - James Blanchard and others (Box 16)
          (no. 215a)
        - James Blanchard and David Peterson (Box 16)
          (no. 215b)
        - Al Neuharth (Box 16)
          (no. 215c)
        - Thomas Eagleton (Box 16)
          (no. 215d)
        - Greater Detroit Chamber of Commerce speaker (Box 16)
          (no. 215e)
      - The making of "Somewhere in Time" at Grand Hotel (1), 1979
        - Bill Erwin and Christopher Reeve (Box 16)
          (no. 217a)
        - Setting up arrival shot with Christopher Reeve (Box 16)
          (no. 217b)
        - Christopher Reeve (Box 16)
          (no. 217c)
        - Setting up interior shot (Box 16)
          (no. 217d)
      - The making of "Somewhere in Time" at Grand Hotel (2), 1979
        - Setting up interior shot (Box 16)
          (no. 217e)
        - Christopher Reeve and friend (Box 16)
          (no. 217f)
        - Interior scene (Box 16)
          (no. 217g)
        - Interior scene (Box 16)
          (no. 217h)
      - Governor's Conference with General George Marshall and Admiral Ernest King, 1945
    - People
      - Guests on Grand Hotel porch, 1890s (Box 16)
        (no. 6)
      - "Grand Hotel bell staff" (Box 16)
        (no. 10)
      - Dan Musser, Jr. (Box 16)
        (no. 11)
      - "The Musser family welcomes First Lady Hillary Rodham Clinton to Mackinac, June 1995" (Box 17)
        (no. 13)
      - "Thomas E. Dewey, attorney general of New York, New York City prosecuting attorney, at Grand Hotel" (Box 16)
        (no. 15a)